Komal Ali

Senior UI/UX Designer

Personal details

Name

Komal Ali

Email address

Komalali.Jhangiani@gmail.com

Address

United kingdom

Skills

Search Engine Optimization/SEM

HTML/CSS

jQuery

Figma

Sketch

Invisionapp

Adobe Creative Suite

Wireframing

Storyboard

Prototyping

Information architecture

Salesforce

CMS/CRM

Agile

WordPress/Joomla

W3C Web Standards

Profile

A Seasoned Creative UX & UI and Creative Designer with over 7+ years of experience brining consumer-level usability to enterprise-level applications. Vast experience with client and stakeholder relationships, along with project management, leadership, and strategy. Possessing a combination of conceptual strength and technical proficiency. Established self-starter and team leader that actively helps and refines all processes necessary to achieve and maintain goals. My focus and competencies include creative direction, user interface design, user experience design, visual design, iOS design, web design, and graphic design.

Employment

Senior UI/UX Designer

Jun 2020 - Present

Primitive

- Participate in user experience research and usability studies;
- Envision how people experience mobile products and bring that vision to life in a way that feels inspired, refined, and even magical.
- Collaborate with UX & UI, technology, content, and digital marketing teams to deliver impeccable digital products;
- Participate in regular design reviews and other team-wide design efforts;
- Ideate and implement simple (intuitive) designs based on trends and client expectations;
- We are looking for smart, passionate, and feedback and energetic candidates, who are articulate, and can work independently and within teams;
- Create intuitive web, mobile, and storyboard feedback and feedback and IoT applications/product interfaces, websites, and responsive design;
- Comfortable with the storyboard feedback and -driven iterative design process;
- Translate ideas into storyboards to create a visual design using prototyping tools.

Senior Creative UI/UX Designer

Apr 2018 - May 2020

SUSAN G. KOMEN FOR THE CURE

- Designed and developed interactive prototypes using Sketch and invision app.
- Managed Web and interactive communication projects from initial consultation through successful launch thewith the ability to handle various projects simultaneously and complete them by a given deadline.
- Designed and implemented web-based user interface using Html, CSS, and jQuery, and directed front-end projects from concept to completion.
- Consulted with a leading International financial technology company in White Plains, NY to assist in the design of the ability to handle various projects simultaneously and complete them with a new enterprise knowledge/document management site.

Tools: Adobe and Google Web Analytics, CMS, Email Marketing Campaign.

UI/UX Designer

Jan 2015 - Mar 2018

AT&T, Dallas, TX

- E-commerce site designs/layouts to maintain a consistent user experience across the product.
- Delivered high quality design docs: sketches, sitemap, user flows, wireframes, mockups, specification.
- Created actionable and intuitive design flows by developing a site-map and high fidelity wireframes.
- Designed, built, and tested interactive prototype to iterate and evolve design concepts of the project.
- Gathered user data through methods such as analytics reporting, task analysis, and participatory design techniques and utilized that data to drive design decisions.
- Defined information architecture and interaction design for several complex web applications using page/user flow diagrams, site maps, and interactive wireframes created in Axure.
- Collaborated with internal Applications team to design and develop an internal ITaaS portal that could be easily rebranded and licensed to our customers. designs

Tools: Email Marketing Campaign, Storyboard UI and Video Editing, Wire Frames, Social Media Campaign (www.att.com).

Designer

Aug 2013 - Dec 2015

HCL Tech, Dallas

- Worked with Sales and Marketing departments to create new and edit existing ads (print & digital), brochures/collateral, logos, trade show materials, infographics, etc.
- Worked with software development department as needed to collaborate on design for web and mobile applications (UI/UX for landing pages)
- Worked with other departments as needed
- Assist internal clients in determining correct design to go along with messaging
- Create materials that convey messages which promote products
- Develop graphics and visual/audio images for product illustrations/animations, logos, etc.
- Review and proofread designs for errors before printing or publishing
- Think creatively to develop new design concepts, graphics, and layouts
- Help establish and enforce UWorld's brand

Education

Computer - Design

Sep 2009 - Jun 2013

University Of Hawaii

Languages

English

Portfolio

https://faisalali.com Password: fai1234